It's cake baking time.
لقد حان وقت إعداد الكعك.
Now, before you can make a cake,
الآن، قبل إعداد الكعك،
you need all of the ingredients to build it.
ستحتاجون إلى جميع المكونات لإعدادها.
So, we have the cake mix.
لدينا خليط الكعك.
We have eggs, milk, and butter.
وبيض وحليب وزبد.
So, we have everything we need,
وكل المكونات التي نحتاجها،
so I'll turn on the oven and then we can start making it.
لذا سأشغِّل الفرن ثم سنبدأ في تحضيرها.
And done. OK. So, work with me here a bit.
ها قد انتهينا. حسنًا. ركزوا معي قليلًا.
I need the cake to be baked before I can have frosting.
أريد خبز الكعك قبل أن أتمكن من تحضير الكريمة.
And I've requested the oven to take the cake batter and turn it into a cake.
لقد طلبت من الفرن أن يخبز خليط الكعك ويحوله إلى كعك.
And when it's done, this timer here will beep,
وعند الانتهاء، سيصدر هذا المؤقت صوتًا،
letting me know that I can get the cake back.
يبلغنا بأنه يمكننا إخراج الكعك.
But I don't need to sit here and wait around for the cake to bake.
لكنني لا أرغب في الجلوس هنا والانتظار حتى يتم خبز الكعك.
I could go do something else.
يمكنني القيام بشيء آخر.
I could even make the frosting right now.
يمكنني تحضير الكريمة الآن.
An XHR object is provided by
يُوفر كائن XHR
the javascript environment and is used to make AJAX requests.
في بيئة javascript ويُستخدم في إنشاء AJAX requests.
And it's like this initial prep stage of making the cake batter.
حيث يشبه مرحلة الإعداد الأولية لتحضير خليط الكعك.
You have to manually do a lot of the steps to
عليك تنفيذ العديد من الخطوات يدويًا
get the request set up and finally, send off.
لإعداد الطلب وإرساله في النهاية.
But then, your code can continue on and do other things.
يمكن أن يتابع الكود بعد ذلك ويؤدي أمور أخرى.
When the response does come back.
عندما يعود الرد.
it's been prepped to handle the return data.
يتم إعداد ذلك للتعامل مع بيانات الرجوع.
With this analogy in mind,
دعونا نفكر في هذه المقارنة،
let's look at the XHR object in detail.
ونتناول كائن XHR بالتفصيل.